Guide to the American Federation of Teachers, Yakima Local 1485 Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- American Federation of Teachers, Yakima Local 1485 records, 1969-1997; 4145-002; 2.00 cubic feet (2 boxes)
  Correspondence, collective bargaining and proposals, Executive Board minutes 1988-1996, arbitration files, and related files of the local. Includes documentation on reductions in the community college's instructional staff due to budget constraints, as well as files related to bargaining procedures.
  View inventory/container list
  Open to all users.
  Donated by Roger Carlstrom, 7/9/1999.
  - AMERICAN FEDERATION OF TEACHERS, LOCAL 1485/YAKIMA VALLEY COLLEGE FEDERATION OF TEACHERS, 1969-1998; RECORD GROUP 1 (Box-folder 1/1-2/22)
    - COLLECTIVE BARGAINING AND CONTRACTS, 1969-1997; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1-1/19)
      - Collective Bargaining Agreements, 1969-1997; Subseries A (Box-folder 1/1-1/15)
        - Negotiated Policies of the Faculty and the Board of Trustees of Yakima Valley College, April 1969 (Box-folder 1/1)
        - Yakima Valley College Negotiated Document, September 4, 1972 (Box-folder 1/2)
        - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers First Contract Proposal, 1973 (Box-folder 1/3)
        - Negotiated Policy Agreement, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 1/4)
        - Corrected Negotiated Policy Agreement, 1973 (Box-folder 1/5)
        - Negotiated Policy Agreement, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/6)
        - Negotiated Policy Agreement, 1876-1977 (Box-folder 1/7)
        - Negotiated Policy Agreement, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1/8)
        - Negotiated Policy Agreement, 1978-1981 (Amended) (Box-folder 1/9)
        - Agreement, September 2, 1981, to June 10, 1983, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 1/10)
        - Agreement, September 1, 1983, to June 7, 1985, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 1/11)
        - Agreement, September 1, 1986, to June 30, 1989, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 1/12)
        - Agreement, January 1, 1990, to June 30, 1992, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 1/13)
        - Agreement, September 1, 1992, to June 30, 1995, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 1/14)
        - Agreement, July 1, 1995, to June 30, 1997, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 1/15)
      - Collective Bargaining Procedures, 1971-1989; Subseries B (Box-folder 1/16-1/17)
        - Collective Bargaining Law and Regulations, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 1/16)
        - Zipper Clause, 1989 (Box-folder 1/17)
      - Joint Agreements, 1989-1998; Subseries C (Box-folder 1/18-1/19)
        - Retirement Contributions from P.T. Faculty, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 1/18)
        - Curriculum/Program- P.E., 1998 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - CONTRACT ENFORCEMENT, 1972-1992; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/20-1/23)
      - First Day of School, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 1/20)
      - Employment Security, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 1/21)
      - Duty of Fair Representation, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 1/22)
      - Political Expression (Yellow Ribbons etc.), 1991-1992 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - ELECTIONS, 1973; SERIES III (Box-folder 1/24)
      - Collective Bargaining Election - Yakima Valley College Federation of Teachers Planning, 1973 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - EXECUTIVE BOARD PROCEEDINGS, 1988-1996; SERIES IV (Box-folder 1/25-2/8)
      - Executive Board Proceedings - Part 1 of 2, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 1/25)
      - Executive Board Proceedings - Part 2 of 2, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 1/26)
      - Executive Board Proceedings - Part 1 of 3, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 1/27)
      - Executive Board Proceedings - Part 2 of 3, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 1/28)
      - Executive Board Proceedings - Part 3 of 3, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 1/29)
      - Executive Board Proceedings - Part 1 of 3, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 1/30)
      - Executive Board Proceedings - Part 2 of 3, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 2/1)
      - Executive Board Proceedings - Part 3 of 3, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 2/2)
      - Executive Board Proceedings - Part 1 of 2, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Executive Board Proceedings - Part 2 of 2, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Executive Board Proceedings, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 2/5)
      - Executive Board Proceedings, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 2/6)
      - Executive Board Proceedings, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Executive Board Proceedings, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - LEGAL PROCEEDINGS, 1981-1992; SERIES V (Box-folder 2/9-2/17)
      - Arbitration: David Black & Inga Wiehl Grievance, 1981 (Box-folder 2/9)
      - Litigation: Carlstrom, et al. v. State, et al. 1982, 1984, 1986, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 2/10)
      - Arbitration: President's Advisory Council, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 2/11)
      - Arbitration: Roddy, Roy G. and Robert C. Ray, 1983 (Box-folder 2/12)
      - Arbitration: Robert A Fisher and Erwina Peterson, 1984 (Box-folder 2/13)
      - Arbitration: Carol Toney, 1985 (Box-folder 2/14)
      - Arbitration: Barbara Mckenna and Catherine Fousha Grievance, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 2/15)
      - Arbitration:SEIB Grievance, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 2/16)
      - Arbitration: Hiring Activities Arbitration, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - REDUCTIONS IN FORCE (RIF), 1985-1992; SERIES VI (Box-folder 2/18-2/20)
      - RIF History of Bargaining-Part 1 of 2, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 2/18)
      - RIF History of Bargaining-Part 2 of 2, 1985-1992 (Box-folder 2/19)
      - RIF-P.E.Dept., 1992 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - TENURE PROCESS, 1993-1997; SERIES VII (Box-folder 2/21-2/22)
      - Extension of Probationary Period, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 2/21)
      - ADA & Tenure Review Process, 1997 (Box-folder 2/22)
  - EDMONDS-EVERETT ASSOCIATION FOR HIGHER EDUCATION, 1975; RECORD GROUP 2 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Edmonds-Everett Association for Higher Education, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 2/23)